Michael Morris



tendoaki@gmail.com



6063440594



linkedin.com/in/michael-morris-00b4b7118



https://mmorris-sandbox.net

Summary

I've been involved in professional web development for 19 years. I am a full stack capable developer, but much of my recent experience has been in the JavaScript sphere, particularly server side with Node is. I have extensive experience with the emerging Single-Spa framework which allows multiple popular frameworks to be used on a website at the same time, or more importantly allows older websites to be divided up into discrete chunks allowing those chunks to be updated. I know and vastly prefer Typescript to vanilla JavaScript.

I am passionate about the BDD process which provides the most value to the client of all the various testing processes out there. I this delivery process to an entire team. I taught that team, around 30 strong, how to use Cucumber with Puppeteer (Google's antecedent to Microsoft Playwright) using binding shim I wrote for them, and then shepherded the development of nearly 1000 functional tests on a code base that was being developed without automated testing before. That testing system also included a data provider mock to decouple front end development from the back end team so the front end coders could do their work regardless if the back end team had the database servers up.

I am fully versed in the construction of deployment pipelines in gitlab, and have set up continuous integration tasks in Circle CI, Travis CI and Jenkins. I thoroughly test code, usually in Cucumber-js, but I'm also familiar with Jest (I've played with Mocha, Chai and Jasmine enough to know I can be up to speed with them quickly). I have used Ansible and constructed playbooks with it.

I know jQuery, Bootstrap, and even abandoned stuff like Prototype.js. I am well versed in the process of updating software from those projects to modern ES6+ frameworks.

I have worked on PHP extensively and I have contributor credits on the Drupal project and PHPUnit.

I have worked with GoLang and C# over the years. I had a 2 year stint with Java writing Cucumber tests in the Java implementation of that framework. I've had to write Python scripts for AWS containers. Oh, yeah, and I have worked with those although not as much as I'd like to. There's very little I can't pick up quickly.

I know how to use Adobe Creative suite, Jira and participate in Agile methodology.

Outside code I play the piano and recorder flutes. Before moving to care for my parents I was active in musical theater in the Mobile AL area. I sing countertenor (highest male vocal range).

Experience



Web Developer

Freelance (Self employed) Jan 2023 - Present (2 months)



Senior Software Developer

Rural Sourcing

Jan 2018 - Jan 2023 (5 years 1 month)

💙 Senior Web Developer

FLEETCOR

Aug 2020 - Dec 2022 (2 years 5 months)

Fleetcor was a client of Rural Sourcing and I was a consultant.

I introduced the entire production staff from Product owners down to Behavior Driven Development, altering the workflow of the entire company to create more accurate and meaningful estimates of development time based on a count of the scenarios and their steps rather than pure speculation.

Built the functional test layer of the application in Node is using cucumber-JS and Puppeteer as browser driver.

Built a mocking engine in Express.js that could accurately simulate the responses of the REST API provided by the backend team in MuleSoft. Prior to this engine being introduced the front end teams (around 20 people) suffered multiple work stoppages when the dev REST API went down - which at worst was a weekly occurrence, usually when they tried to deploy something the first time.

Served as Interim lead application designer for two months. I later learned Fleetcor had considered hiring me directly to fill the post, but the buyout requested by RSI under the anti-poaching clause of the contract was too high for them.

Implemented a decision to move the application away from a framework-less approach built on the Hugo static site generator to a React site. The new designer chose to use a micro-frontend architecture using the Single Spa framework, but left the details to me, so the following was done:

- Micro-frontends were to be built in Typescript. I had to lead multiple retraining classes in support of this.
- Each page of the site was to be moved to its own repository with its own production pipeline. I wrote all of the supporting CI scripts in GitLab for this and created all project templates to be used.

Web Developer

McKenney's, Inc.

Feb 2020 - Mar 2020 (2 months)

This was a six week contract with RSI.

McKenney's provides HVAC and smart building optimization services for some of the largest structures in the Atlanta area. Some of these structures have in excess of 90,000 data points reporting every 15 minutes. They have a brilliant engineer on staff to gather and collate this information, and I was tasked to build a front end for him to make the information he'd gathered more accessible. This engagement was for six weeks.

The backend already in place was in MVC Razor. I learned how to get some templates and with a little guidance did what little C# code I needed to support the pages he needed. We chose to go with a combination of AgGrid to write the reports, and CodeMirror to allow his team to write in their own

report formulae into the application in Excel style. A custom multiselect tool was also developed to sort through the thousands of possible data points.



Automated QA Programmer

Enterprise

Apr 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 10 months)

Contract position while at RSI. I wrote Cucumber end to end tests for an Angular application in Java.

₩ Web Developer

Lexington-Fayette Urban County Government (LFUCG)

Jan 2017 - Aug 2017 (8 months)

I was charged with general maintenance and expansion of the city website using Drupal 8, including the addition of a parks map system using ArchGis.



Web Developer

Tombras

Jul 2013 - Aug 2016 (3 years 2 months)

I built advertising focused sites using Wordpress and Drupal.

Web Developer

Webbed Sphere Inc.

Jun 2012 - Jun 2013 (1 year 1 month)

PHP, JavaScript and CSS work on a custom in house e-commerce solution. Attempted to migrate the site to Magento, but Magento could not be made to work with a catalog of around 6 million items.

• Web Developer

eGovernment Solutions

May 2010 - Apr 2012 (2 years)

This company provides government support web applications for counties in the state of Tennessee, allowing citizens to pay fines and taxes online. The software had no automated tests at all, and it was at this time I began the process of learning automated tests to try to make the task more doable. The program was entirely in house and written to support IE 6. Weaning the software from IE 6 only was high on the task list which led to one of the more interesting bits of code I ever wrote.

The software was not only an online portal, it was an in office management suite. The clients wanted one click printing of documents, which isn't possible in JavaScript because of hackers. However, by contract the physical server was to be placed in the office. I took advantage of this unusual arrangement of the server being on the same local network as the printers they wanted to print with and wrote a PHP LDAP library to drive the printing.

I also optimized many of the report queries. The most memorable was one that took 8 hours to run before I rewrote it to run in 4 minutes - three of which were spent on a temporary table creation query to copy the data over to something normalized.

Education

W University of Kentucky

Theater 1996 - 2000

Skills

AgGrid • Webpack • React.js • TypeScript • Software Testing • JUnit • Gitlab • Web Applications • User Interface Design • Single Page Applications